Only God knows.
We're going to resume the lecture.
Well, my guiding angels are here today, both in and out of body.
I have permission to ask what I'm going to ask.
My guiding angels are here.
So my guiding angels are here.
So I don't take credit for anything I say.
So acknowledging the presence of divinity tends to reinforce when you affirm the presence
of divinity and give thanks to the Lord, you strengthen the guidance that you get from
the Lord.
That's true.
Resist.
Yeah.
So acknowledging...
Acknowledging divinity as the source of your existence and thanking God.
So giving thanks to God and acknowledging God tends to reinforce the divine energy within
your own psyche.
Yes.
So even in the pits of hell...
Where I was, like, forsaken forever.
I mean, it was forever.
Unbelievable.
I mean, forever more.
Eternally, you would be cut off from love or salvation forever.
In the word forever, you got what forever means.
And that was terrifying.
Yes.
And that's when a voice from within me said,
if there is a God, I ask him for help.
And then all of hell disappeared
and I was suddenly in a radiance
in which the divinity of all that exists
shone forth like a radiant light from all that exists.
That was over 800.
900.
950.
945.
That moment was 945, yeah.
From minus 500 or whatever it was.
From 945's negative to 945's positive.
I think you're joking.
The divinity revealed itself as all that exists.
Yeah.
To know that you are an expression of divinity
as you.
You are an expression of divinity as you.
I am an expression of divinity as you.
Yeah.
So if I can love God,
the beauty of the translator shines forth.
Unmistakable.
The beauty of the translator is shown as it is.
There is no room for misunderstanding.
So,
you're very blessed.
I'm very blessed to have you today.
We are very blessed to have you with us today.
And Dr. Moon and all our visitors
because of them, this occasion arose.
And the charm of the Korean people came with you.
The charm.
Okay, we'll go back to the slides, back to the mundane.
From the sublime to the mundane, yeah?
Well, to become educated about the levels of consciousness
and the subject of our lectures is a very singular discovery.
Oh, let's see.
I think this is very interesting,
the levels of consciousness and social problems,
because it's always presumed because of political gain,
the political gain,
to blame it on society or blame it on a certain culture.
Yeah, it's the culture's fault.
It's the culture's fault.
Well, if it was the culture's fault,
then everybody who grew up poor would be poor.
No, many people grew up poor, and they transcend to that.
People that grew up rich often also become poor.
So, yeah?
What?
Oh, yes, I keep forgetting he's there.
Oh, okay.
He is.
The levels of consciousness and the relationships of these things
are very interesting.
Because for political gain,
politicians keep on adding to the causes of culture or certain things.
But that doesn't make sense.
That's why it's very interesting to study this relationship.
It's very interesting.
So, from this slide, we can stop blaming social conditions.
You know, the world is full of political gain
by blaming one group for another group, you see?
So, if we study these things,
we can stop adding social responsibility to other things.
But all the difficulties,
the social difficulties,
the political difficulties,
can be overcome by personal integrity and striving.
Yes.
All right.
Does anybody have any questions about this level that you see that
experientially what the people are doing is living out their own level of consciousness?
Yes.
Do you have any questions about this?
What people are experiencing is their own level of consciousness.
They are experiencing it as their own level of consciousness.
Yeah.
So, and this is why we say that you influence the world by what you are.
So, what you are, then, is what influences the world,
not by what you do or you say,
but by what you do.
But by what you become.
So, the best thing we can do for our children, then,
is to try to provide for the advancement of their level of consciousness.
So, there's a great benefit to a religious upbringing,
spiritual upbringing, spiritual integrus,
whether it's Confucianism or Taoism or Buddhism or Christianity or Hindu,
they all acknowledge a higher power and a gradient of being.
That you can become better than you are through endeavor and meditation and service to others.
Yeah.
So, like a cork in water, you rise to your own level of buoyancy.
Right.
So, to be loving towards all of life in all of its expressions
is the greatest gift you can give to the world.
So, when you see the little beetle,
I was talking about my little black beetle.
When you see the little black beetle down there in the alley,
and you step around the beetle like that,
the world is now a better place than if you went,
I always like to talk about this cockroach.
When the cockroach is on the ground,
if you avoid it a little bit,
the world becomes a better place because of it.
Rather than stepping on it.
Next slide, Eddie.
Next slide, yeah.
Yeah.
So, you can tell our students, they always walk over beetles.
Anybody who's been in these classes, they always step over the beetle.
Okay.
So, this is just reading the levels of consciousness
and the incidence.
So, we'll go to the next one, yeah.
Right?
Yes.
So, the next section is on spiritual teachers
about which there's a great deal of discussion.
The next section is about spiritual teachers.
Because of all the books and all the gurus
and the famous and infamous teachers,
the student is often confused which way to go.
Because the reason that we need to know this is
because students and students of spiritual books
are always confused about spiritual teachers.
Yes.
And many questions we get in the mail, you know,
asked about a certain teacher, you know.
So, what we try to do is
we publish the list of 100
integrous teachers over time.
We have a list of teachers
that we ask to measure.
There are 20 teachers.
And what level of, what is the level of their teaching, say, what is the level of their teaching?
So, a higher number doesn't necessarily mean that that teacher is better for you right now.
Because a teacher who calibrates at 500 would be better for you than a teacher who calibrates at 800, but you don't understand anything he's saying.
Alright, so we wanted to print out,
what are the characteristics that define the excellence of a teacher,
so that the student can become independent of the calibrated levels that they can learn for themselves?
Yes.
Alright, so we say that truth is not limited to the possession of only certain teachers or people, that it's really open to everyone. Truth is all-inclusive.
Truth is not a possession of one particular teacher, and that it contains everything.
And that it is available to everything.
Yeah, so truth is all-inclusive, and it's not given out as a secret.
And it's non-sectarian.
It's not the exclusive property of any one religion or spiritual pathway.
So there are great teachers in all the world's bona fide religions.
The great teachers can be of any religion.
No secrets to be revealed, hidden, sold, magical formulas or mysteries.
People say for $10,000, I will tell you,
there are no secrets to be revealed, hidden, sold, magical formulas or mysteries.
There are no secrets to be revealed, hidden, sold, magical formulas or mysteries.
So, availability.
Open to all.
Non-exclusive.
No secrets to be revealed, hidden, or sold, magical formulas, so.
There are teachers out there that for $5,000 will tell you the secrets.
I'll do it for $4,000.
I'll buy it.
They say they'll do it for $4,000.
So then, you need compassion for the teacher,
who is not fully developed as a teacher.
So, you pray for the teacher that will reach full enlightenment.
So, you need compassion for the teacher that will reach full enlightenment.
All right.
So, a true teacher,
So, a true teacher, there is,
nothing to gain or lose
there's no profit
no gain or loss
if you think he's great
that's fine
and if you don't think
he's great that's fine
because the spiritual
ego is the only thing that would make you
create fame and fortune
and to be famous
and all over the world
because
only the spiritual ego
is trying to become famous
and want to be praised
to a true teacher
there's nothing to gain or lose
because
that which you know
with the capital
capital K
is beyond approval
disapproval
agreement
disagreement
money
fame
all those things are foolish
because what you know
is beyond profit and honor
alright
we have a lot of things that define truth here
it's independent of opinion
independent of opinion
so
you know I got to get
ourself emails of people's various opinions
and I don't pay any attention to them
because
they're not talking about anything having to do with truth or reality
they're talking about their own perception
and perception
is not of any particular interest
the truth has nothing to do with opinions
so I get a lot of emails from many people
but I don't care about that at all
they only care about their opinions and opinions so I don't care about that at all
so I don't care about that at all
they're only talking about their own perception
yeah see truth is independent of opinion
it's not anti-anything
and falsehood is not its enemy
but really the absence of truth
so truth is either present or not present
so truth has to do with opinion
the truth is either present or not present
truth has to do with the essence of things
falsehood has to do with perception of things
now to convey the truth or to teach the truth or to make it available
there are no required memberships or dues
there's no regulations
you don't have to dress in some funny way
you don't have to take any oaths
there's no rules
no conditions
and you don't
there's no conditions, no oaths, no rules
no requirements, no demands
to make truth available
you don't have to demand anything
you don't have to make any rules
you don't have to make any conditions
that sounds pretty good doesn't it
I'll go for that
okay
no requirement, no regulations
no oaths, no rules
no conditions
to know the truth then is volitional only
nothing is required
all right
so the conveyor of truth is non-controlling
not interested in controlling people
spiritual purity has no interest
in the personal lives of students
the conveyor of truth is not interested in control
and spiritual purity is not interested in the personal lives of students
now in Sedona we had a spiritual teacher
who is now left
but it was the exact opposite of this
told everybody what they must do
who they could go to bed with
who they could ride in a car with
to give them the money
sign over all their property to him
now there is no one in Sedona
who is against this at all
who has to sleep with someone
who has to wear certain clothes
who has to drive certain cars
he controlled all of this
yeah
what you should eat
what you should dress
all about your sex life
all about your money
what your family should do
what kind of car you should drive in
now what in the world would anybody who is spiritually advanced care about all that
all right
so
two spiritual teachings are free of force or intimidation
no force or intimidation
no brainwashing
worship of the leader
indoctrination
rituals
intrusions into private life
so the true spiritual teacher then
teaches by content
what we talk about
but teaches primarily by the radiation
of the energy field of that
which the teacher is in truth.
영적인 스승은
내용으로도 가리키지만
1차적으로는
그가 방사하는 영적인 에너지로서
가르침을 펼칩니다.
It comes through as a radiation
from the aura of the teacher
to the aura of the student.
그의 가르침은
스승의 오라로부터
학생의 오라로 전달됩니다.
광이로서 전달됩니다.
And the aura does not belong to the teacher
그 오라는 스승에게
귀속되지 않습니다.
Because that energy that the teacher has
came from his teacher.
왜냐하면
그 스승이 가진 에너지는
그 스승의 스승에게로부터
왔기 때문입니다.
That which radiates forth
from the consciousness
of the teacher
was already a gift to the teacher.
그의 의식에서
발현되는 그것은
이미 다른 스승으로부터의
선물이었습니다.
So the teacher
out of humility
is grateful
that he has been allowed
to serve such a function.
그러므로
겸손함을 가지고
그 스승은
이제 스승의 역할을
할 수 있다는 것에 대해서
감사하게 여깁니다.
So it creates
greater humility
rather than
magnifying the ego.
You say,
Dear Lord,
I give thanks to Thee
that I have been assigned
this mission
by which I may serve Thee
and my fellow men.
Amen.
이러한 것에 대한 이해는
애고를 강화시키는 것 대신
겸손함을 강화시키고
제가 당신의 가르침을
제 동료 인간에게
전달할 수 있게 되신 것에 대해서
신에게 감사를 드리게 됩니다.
Okay.
So then,
you become
the teacher becomes
aligned with serving
God and his fellow man
serving others
by virtue of that
what he has become
to be that.
자신이 된 그것으로서
신과 동료 인간과
정렬되게 됩니다.
가르침으로서 정렬시켜줍니다.
Yeah.
Okay.
So the next slide.
I can't read anything.
Oh, non-binding.
I remember when I was young,
I was invited to become
a member of a certain group
and I found out
that you had to take an oath.
제가 어릴 때
어떤 사람들과 어울리기 위해서
그들 외에 멤버가 되기 위해서는
어떤 선서를 해야 된다는 것을
알게 되었습니다.
And yet, at age 12,
I think I was 12,
열두 살 때였는데요.
I knew better than to take an oath.
저는 그 선서를 해서는
안 된다는 것을 알았습니다.
Okay.
So I can discuss,
I can reveal this result.
이것에 대해서
Is it okay?
Yes.
Alright.
Because oaths are binding
from one lifetime to the next.
왜냐하면 선서를 하지 않아야 하는 것은
선서는 생을 거듭해서
그 사람을 묶기 때문입니다.
So a true teacher wants you to be free
and not bound.
진정한 스승은 당신이
자유롭기를 원하지
묶이기를 원하지 않습니다.
So, therefore,
students are free to come and go
without trying to persuade them,
coerce them, threaten them,
intimidate them,
excommunicate them,
tax them,
or chop their heads off.
그렇기 때문에
스승은 학생들이 자유롭게 오가길 원합니다.
설득하지도 않고,
강제력을 행사하지도 않고,
겁을 주지도 않고,
세금을 매기지도 않고,
머리를 잘라버리지도 않습니다.
There are people who make converts
by giving you your choice,
to either join them
or become beheaded.
그 스승을 따르게 되는 사람 중에는
여기 들어오든지,
아니면 머리가 잘리든지의 선택권에서
그렇게 결정한 사람들도 있습니다.
So, real integrity allows for freedom,
allows you to say yes or no
without any consequences.
And if a person declines,
then the proper thing for the teacher
is to pray for that person's enlightenment.
그래서 진정한 스승은 자유를 허락하고
그에게 yes나 no를 선택할 기회를 주고
그들이 만약 거부한다면
그들을 위해서
그들이 알만한 적당한 길을 선택하도록 기도해 줍니다.
All right.
So the teacher is inspirational.
Truth avoids glamorization, seduction,
and theatrics.
진실은 영감을 고치시키고
어떤 유혹하는 것이나
그 다음에 어떤 과시하는 것
이런 것을 모두 피합니다.
Truth is devoid of neediness of worldly wealth,
prestige, titles, pomp, edifices.
진실은 세상적인 부와
명성과 어떤 거대한 구조물
이런 것들을 모두 필요로 하지 않습니다.
All right.
So truth stands on its own.
진실은 그 자체로 섭니다.
Without formalities, theatrics, drum and bugle,
orchestras, and dancing girls.
진실은 어떤 과대 포장이라든지
오케스트라 뮤직이라든지
아니면 춤추는 여인들 없이도
스스로 그 자체로서 섭니다.
And I think in its higher form
it also avoids extremes of asceticism.
그리고 또 한 가지는
어떤 극단주의적인 금욕주의도 거부합니다.
Yeah, that occurs in the Hindu tradition.
그것은
Yeah.
Asceticism to an extreme degree
where you're profoundly emaciated
and falling over from hunger and weakness
is not a necessity.
I think.
힌두 전통에서 발생한
아주 극단주의적인 어떤 금욕주의
배고픔으로 인해서 바짝 말라서 쓰러지는
그러한 것은 결코 필요하지 않습니다.
Truth itself fulfilling and complete.
It is already total and complete.
Has no need to proselytize,
gain adherence, sign up members, followers,
send in dues.
진실은 자기 전통에서
충족적이며
이미 완전하고
완전 무결하기 때문에
전도할 필요도 없고
추종자들을 얻으려고 노력하거나
멤버들을 이렇게
사인업 시키지도 않습니다.
Yeah.
Now,
there is non-involvement in worldly affairs.
So you're in the world
but not of it.
Yeah.
I'm in the world but not of the world.
세상에 있기지만 세상적이지는 않습니다.
The world is as it is.
있는 그대로 있을 뿐입니다.
So there's no need to control others.
You see how much of the conflicts of the world
are due to one group or person trying to control others.
If I think this way, you have to think this way.
Seeking agreement.
Why does the world seek agreement?
Yeah.
세상에 많은 문제는
누군가를 통제하려고 하는 것 때문에 일어납니다.
모두 자신이 하고자 하는 것에
동의를 구하려고 하기 때문에
이러한 폭력들이 발생합니다.
You have to think the way they think.
Why is it people insist that you think the way they must think?
우리는 상대방이 생각하는 대로 생각하도록 강요받습니다.
왜 우리가 그래야 할까요?
Okay, so you can believe in Christmas or not.
당신은 크리스마스를 믿어도 되고 믿지 않아도 됩니다.
If I believe in Christmas, you don't have to.
제가 크리스마스를 믿는다고 해서 당신이 꼭 그래야 할 필요는 없습니다.
Yeah.
If I don't believe in Christmas, you don't have to stop believing in Christmas
because I don't believe in Christmas.
제가 크리스마스를 믿지 않는다고 해서
당신이 크리스마스를 믿는 것을 그만둬야 할 필요도 없습니다.
So you see how interesting.
The daily news is when you see it goes back and forth
for these groups trying to force other people
to think and see and perceive the way they do.
그래서 이러한 것을 이해하게 되면
우리가 매일 신문에서 보는 것처럼
다른 사람이 자기가 생각하는 대로
자신이 지각하는 대로
자신이 믿는 대로 다른 사람들에게 강요하는 것이
얼마나 우습다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
Now you say, why is the human that way?
That he wants everybody to agree with him.
Why?
인간은 다른 사람들이 자신과 똑같이
생각하고 행동하기를 원하는 것일까요?
Why must everybody agree with you?
왜 모든 사람이 당신에게 동의해야 합니까?
So the core of that which is anti-God
and anti-freedom
is the narcissistic core of the ego.
신에게 부정적인 것의 핵심은
자기애적인 애고의 애고입니다.
Everybody has...
He has to see it my way.
모든 사람들이 내가 보는 것처럼 봐야 되죠.
Because I am right and you are wrong.
왜냐하면 내가 옳고 당신은 그르기 때문입니다.
So that's egotism.
이러한 것이 바로 자기중심주의입니다.
So the opposite of God, the enemy of God
is the narcissistic core of the ego.
그렇기 때문에 신에게 반대하는 것
그리고 신에게 반대하는 것이
신에게 대항하는 것은
자기애적인 애고의 핵심입니다.
So the core of the ego is me, me, me, me, me.
그래서 애고의 핵심은
나, 나, 나를 찾는 바로 그것입니다.
Yeah, me, me, me.
Vote for me.
Buy me.
Photograph me.
Worship me.
Send your money.
Send your emails.
Send your...
That machine that they talk on.
Blogs.
Send me your blogs.
블로그도 좀 보내주시고.
The world is suffocating with blogism.
세상은 지금 블로그리즘에 의해서 아주 숨막힐 지경입니다.
So all that people do when they make an utterance
is a verbalized blog.
그래서 어떤 사람이 무언가를 얘기할 때
You mean blog?
블로그.
Blog.
사람들이 말할 때 블로그리즘.
블로그리즘.
우리가 블로그로 하는 그런 것들이 언어와되고 있는 것이나 마찬가지입니다.
So when you boil it down,
there's only God and blogs.
그래서 이것을 바닥까지 들여다보게 되면
신과 블로그만 남게 됩니다.
Now, God doesn't know how to work a computer.
그런데 신은 컴퓨터를 사용할지 모릅니다.
He doesn't know how to text.
문자를 보낼 수 있는 능력이 없습니다.
So you break the world, the tragedies of the world down,
and you begin to see them as humor and absurdity.
세상의 문제들을 이렇게 차근차근 나열해 보게 되면
거기서 휴머를 보게 되고 이것이 부조리하다는 것을 알게 됩니다.
So then there is only knowing the truth and ignorance.
그렇기 때문에 결국에는
진실을 아는 것과 무지만이 남게 됩니다.
So Jesus Christ said that there is only one source of sin
and there is only one sin and that is of ignorance.
그래서 예수님께서는 죄의 근원은 단 하나이고
그것은 무지라고 말했습니다.
There is only ignorance.
오로지 무지만이 있을 뿐입니다.
And that which we consider evil and all that is all profound ignorance.
그래서 우리가 악마라고 여기는 그러한 것들은
사실은 아주 심온한 무지일 뿐입니다.
The Buddha said the same thing.
부처님도 같은 말씀을 하셨습니다.
Krishna said the same thing.
I say the same thing.
박사님도 같은 말씀을 하셨습니다.
A lot of them out there are just plain stupid.
세상에 많은 사람들은 그냥 어리석은 짓을 하고 있을 뿐입니다.
The karmically earn the right to hear the truth
and be exposed to the truth
just as one karmically evolves to the place
that they can comprehend the truth and recognize the truth.
진실을 배우고 진실에 노출되기 위해서
사람은 카르마적으로 그것을 획득해야 됩니다.
So the Buddha said many can listen but few can hear.
그래서 부처님은 많은 사람들이 진실을
들을 수는 있지만 진정으로
들은 사람들은 적다고 말했습니다.
Many listen but few can hear.
많은 사람들이 들을 수는 있으나
아주 소수만이 이해할 수 있다고 했습니다.
So the Buddha spoke to those who are able to hear.
To those who can hear, he spoke the Buddha.
The Buddha spoke to those who can hear.
부처님은 들을 수 있는 사람들은
이해할 수 있는 사람들에게 말했습니다.
So a wise prayer is to pray to be able to hear.
그래서 현명한 기도는 이해할 수 있도록 해달라고 기도하는 것입니다.
And then your guiding angels get your willingness
and see to it that you come into the presence of a teacher
who will explain what you need to know
and willing to know and able to grasp.
그렇게 기도하게 되면 당신의 안내를
당신의 안내를 알 수 있습니다.
당신의 안내 천사가 당신이
그것을 진실을 이해할 수 있고
듣고 이해할 수 있도록 전달해 줄 수 있는
스승의 현존에 있게끔 해줍니다.
Yeah, so the Buddha was a great teacher.
He spoke from wisdom.
부처는 지혜로부터 지혜의 말씀을 하신
훌륭한 스승이었습니다.
He said, let those who can hear, hear.
들을 수 있는 자만이 이해할 수 있는 사람들에게
들을 수 있는 자만이 듣도록 들어라.
라고 말했습니다.
Let those who can hear, hear.
I like that.
들을 수 있는 자만이 들어라.
Uh-huh.
호케스 밥스님이 좋아하시는 겁니다.
Then you're here.
Because that's non-controlling, you know.
And he's acknowledging that your capacity to hear
is considerably your own karmic inheritance.
You may not be able to hear, and it's not your fault
because at this point you cannot hear yet.
Yeah.
왜냐하면 그러한 것은 통제하는 것이 아니니까요.
부처님께서는 당신이 들을 수 있는 능력은
당신의 카르마적인 어떤 자산이라는 것을
인정하셨습니다.
All right.
So, truth then tries to inspire and lead people
to the truth or to the conditions that allow you
to hear the truth.
So that's why humility is constantly stressed
in all spiritual teachings.
Humility, yes.
Uh-huh.
진실은, uh-huh.
진실은 당신에게, 당신이 그것을 이해할 수 있는 조건들을
허락해 주기 때문에, 그래서 겸손함이라는 것이
계속해서 강조되는 이유입니다.
So truth does not seek to control others.
진실은 다른 이들을 통제하려 하지 않습니다.
It doesn't want to have to convince others or force others.
진실은 다른 사람을 확신시키려고 하지도 않고
강제하지도 않습니다.
You will go to the next slide.
And, uh, there are no issues or positionalities.
어떤 문제도 없고 위치성도 있지 않습니다.
God doesn't need help.
신은 도움을 필요로 하지 않습니다.
People, I think, they're helping God.
I will, if you don't believe the way I believe,
I'll cut your head off.
And he thinks that way you're helping God.
So we have to become humble and realize
God doesn't need your help.
그렇기 때문에 우리는 신이 우리의 도움을 필요로 하지 않는다는 것을
느끼고 겸손해져야 합니다.
God's made it this far without your help.
신은 당신의 도움 없이도 이렇게 훌륭하십니다.
Yeah, so the more sophisticated,
we become, we become aware that
divinity is like an infinite source of energy,
infinitely powerful source of energy,
and that within that field,
you are free to move about or come or go.
Yes.
우리가 점점 더 진보함에 따라서 우리는 신성이라고 하는 것이
에너지의 무한한 근원이라는 것을 이해하고
그 안에서 우리는 자유롭게 움직일 수 있습니다.
All right, so that which all spiritual truth,
infinite spiritual truth is beyond proof.
모든 영적인 진실은 증명을 넘어서 있습니다.
That which is provable is within the linear domain,
the Newtonian domain.
증명할 수 있는 것은 선형적인 뉴톤적 영역에 속하는 것입니다.
All right, that which is provable,
is obviously not divine.
그렇기 때문에 분명히 증명할 수 있는 것은 신성한 것이 아닙니다.
There's no way you can prove the infinite.
무한을 증명할 수 있는 방법은 존재하지 않습니다.
Many of the journals having to do with religion and things
calibrate in the 300s.
They're all about theology and God and all this.
When you calibrate them,
they're like in the 300s.
So what they're talking about is not the reality,
but intellectualizations about the reality.
종교나 그러한 신학에 관한 그러한 학술 잡지들은
측정을 해본다면 300대로 측정됩니다.
이 사실이 말하는 것은 그들은 신성이라고 하는 것을
실상이 아닌 단지 주지화하고 있는 것입니다.
All right.
Now, this one is...
One of the basics to know that is that life is not subject to death.
Now, there's the law of the preservation of energy.
Energy cannot be destroyed.
It can only change form.
Matter cannot be destroyed.
알아야 하실 아주 기본적인 것은 생명이 파괴될 수 없다는 것입니다.
진량 보존의 법칙과 에너지 법칙,
보존의 법칙이 있듯이 에너지가 오로지 형상만을 바꿀 수 있듯이 생명도 그러합니다.
All right.
Now, more recently discovered is the third principle.
That is, the truth cannot be, life cannot be destroyed.
Resist.
Life cannot be destroyed.
So matter cannot be destroyed.
Energy cannot be destroyed.
And now, the third great discovery is that,
that life cannot be destroyed.
Material can only change form from one form to another.
Energy can only change from one form to another,
but you cannot destroy energy.
생명이...
What?
Oh, oh, I forgot about it.
에너지가 소멸될 수 없고, 진량이, 물질이 소멸될 수 없듯이,
세 번째 위대한 발견은 생명도 파괴될 수 없다는 것입니다.
So we're all familiar with the basic concept that matter cannot be destroyed.
It can only change form.
우리는 모두 물질이 파괴될 수 없고, 단지 형태만을 바꿀 수 있다는 것을 잘 알고 있습니다.
And energy cannot be destroyed.
It can only change form.
에너지도 파괴될 수 없고, 오로지 형상만을 바꿀 수 있습니다.
And now, a third discovery.
세 번째,
세 번째 발견입니다.
The third discovery.
What is the third discovery again?
Life cannot be destroyed.
It can only change form.
세 번째 발견은 생명도 파괴될 수 없고, 단지 형상만을 바꿀 수 있을 뿐입니다.
Okay.
So, known before was that matter and energy cannot be destroyed.
But nowhere have I ever read that life cannot be destroyed.
이전에 에너지와 물질이,
에너지와 물질이,
파괴될 수 없다는 것은 모두 알고 있었지만,
누구도 생명이 파괴될 수 없고, 오로지 형상만을 바꿀 수 있다는 것은 들어본 적이 없을 것입니다.
Alright. Like matter and energy,
life can only change form, but you cannot destroy life.
Life cannot be destroyed.
에너지와 물질과 마찬가지로 생명은 파괴될 수 없고, 오로지 형상만을 바꿀 수 있습니다.
Life cannot be destroyed. Resist.
It can only change form.
So,
the only thing that can happen if they chop off your head is that you leave your physical body and there you are in your etheric body.
그렇기 때문에, 누군가 당신의 머리를 잘라낸다면, 육체성은 사라지지만, 당신은 이제 이 에테르체에 있게 됩니다.
So, I've been in my physical body and thought that's me.
저는 육체 없이 에테르체에 있었습니다.
있어본 적이 있습니다.
Then I've been out of my body.
저는 육체를 벗어난 적도 있습니다.
And the body was over there.
육체는 저기에 있었고.
And consciousness says, this is me.
의식은, 이게 나다 라고 말했습니다.
Well, the body is there and me is here. How can that be?
육체는 저기 있고, 저는 여기 있고. 이것이 어떻게 가능할까요?
Because you also have an etheric body.
왜냐하면 당신은 또한 에테르체도 가지고 있기 때문입니다.
The spirit, the soul, that which leaves the body at the point of death, yeah.
영과 영혼은 육신이 죽을 때 몸을 떠납니다.
So, a third great teaching is that life cannot be destroyed, it can only change form.
그러므로 세 번째 위대한 가르침은, 생명은 파괴될 수 없고 오로지 형상만을 바꿀 수 있다는 것입니다.
That's true at the level of the absolute resist.
That is true at the level of the absolute, life cannot be destroyed, it can only change form.
Isn't that good news?
좋은 소식 아닌가요?
If you don't like being a human being, you can come back. Hop, hop, hop, bunny, bunny. Hop, hop, bunny, bunny.
사람이 되기 싫으면 말로 태어나실 수도 있습니다.
새로 태어나실 수도 있고요.
I thought it would be great to be an eagle. Go up a mile in the sky, and ten miles away you can spot a mouse.
Wow, that must be something.
독수리가 된다는 것은 굉장히 멋질 거라고 생각했습니다.
한 천 미터도 넘게 올라가서 쥐를 볼 수 있는 능력을 갖는다.
You don't even need glasses.
안경도 필요 없습니다.
The eagle, miles away, can spot a mouse from over a thousand feet.
Now, let's see. I think that's the last of the slides, and then we're going to go on to more interesting things.
I don't know what they are, but that's what they say.
What was the end of this?
Oh, yes.
Simplicity.
One sees the intrinsic beauty of that which is beyond appearance and form.
So, in a moment of mystical revelation, the overwhelming beauty of what exists, you're knocked out by the beauty, beauty.
그렇기 때문에
압도적인 드러남의 상태에서 모든 것에 내지 않은 본질적인 아름다움이 당신을 쓰러트려 버립니다.
Truth does not do anything. It just is.
And its influence is as a consequence of that which it is.
진실은 어떤 것도 하지 않으며, 모든 것을 그저 그것의 존재로서 영향을 미칩니다. 모든 것에.
Okay.
And truth is not emotional.
Emotionality is based on perception.
진실은 감정적이지 않습니다.
감정성이라는 것은 지각에 근거한 것입니다.
Truth is sought, is found through freedom, rather than rules and restrictions.
진실은 자유를 통해서 따르게 되며, 따르게 되지, 룰이나 이런 것으로 인해서 지켜지지 않습니다.
And true spiritual teachers are respected,
but they reject personal adulation or specialness.
진정한 스승은 존경되기는 하나, 개인적인 찬양은 거절합니다.
The recognition of truth is natural.
It's devoid of induced, altered states of consciousness,
various manipulating energies up and down the spine,
and magical breathing,
and the power of the mind.
Let's do this one.
That calibrates over 190, 195.
Think of those students all over the planet doing,
calibrates at 190.
You're dumber than when you started it.
이 호흡법은 195로 측정되며, 이걸 하게 되면 당신이 시작하기 전보다 더 어리석게 되죠.
So, alright, we're almost done.
It's wise then,
to really check out the integrity of a teacher,
a teaching, a method,
the fact that it's called yoga.
Oh, it's yoga.
I'll give you a yoga.
Try this yoga.
Try that yoga.
The fact that it's called a yoga,
it's a mystical, magical,
better than butter is yoga.
Yoga spread.
Yoga talks.
Yoga socks.
Yoga shoes.
Yoga flowers.
Okay, I'll do all over.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
It was my pleasure.
Thank you for being our translator.
And tell the people what are we going to do.
I don't know what we're going to do.
We're going to take a 15-minute break here.
And anyone who has a question,
if they will please line up on this side.
Oh.
The auditorium.
Anyone who needs book signing,
we did sign a lot of the books.
But if you want something signed,
take it to this side of the auditorium.
And we'll resume in about 15 minutes.
We're a little bit over,
so we'll probably run over a little bit in the break.
But we're a little bit over.
And this lady over here that's in the Korean costume,
come here.
This is typical of the Korean dress.
It's so beautiful.
And I wanted all of you to take a look.
Take a good look at it.
Come here.
I want them to see your dress.
A lot of the people here in the U.S.
haven't seen the traditional Korean.
Thank you.
Thank you for your playing.
Isn't that beautiful?
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Okay.
We'll resume in about 15 minutes then.